Guide to the John Fitz Gibbon Papers M2166
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
John Fitz Gibbon papers
1955-2009
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Fitz Gibbon, Jane
Fitz Gibbon, John
KPFA (Radio station: Berkeley, Calif.)
M2166
12 Linear Feet (24 boxes and 1 CD-R)
266 megabyte(s) contents of 1 CD-R in collection
Writing, photographs, media, and other material from Northern Californian art critic, collector, and teacher John Fitz Gibbon.
Biographical / Historical
John Grattan Fitz Gibbon (1934 – 2009) was an art critic, professor of art history, KPFA broadcaster, and collector of postwar Californian art. From the 1960s onward, he was heavily involved in the Northern Californian art scene, where he was friends with and wrote extensively about a number of renowned artists of the period, including Robert Arneson, Elmer Bischoff, Joan Brown, Don Hazlitt, Jim Nutt, Robert Colescott, and Richard Diebenkorn. Born in Los Angeles on July 12th, 1934, Fitz Gibbon came of age in Pasadena, Laguna Beach, and Berkeley, enrolling in University of California at Berkeley in 1952 before transferring to Yale the following year. He graduated from that institution with a B.A. in English in 1956 as a Scholar of the First Rank. In 1959, Fitz Gibbon became an English teacher at Berkeley High School, where he remained for a decade while simultaneously working at the Southern Pacific Railroad switchyards in Oakland. During this time he also became immersed in art history, hosting a KPFA radio show themed around art criticism from 1962 – 1969. In 1969, he was appointed as a Visiting Associate Professor of Art History at UC Berkeley. Later that same year, he was hired as the Chairman of the Art Department at Sacramento State College, and in 1971 he became the Associate Professor of Art History at the same institution. Fitz Gibbon would go on to teach art history at Sacramento State for the following two decades, recruiting a number of his artist friends to teach in the art department throughout the 1970s and 80s. During this time, Fitz Gibbon wrote dozens of essays, reviews, and exhibition catalogs, eventually winning a National Endowment for the Arts award for art criticism. Through the 1970s, John and his wife Jane Fitz Gibbon hosted a series of ‘Events’: choreographed performances and theatrical celebrations inspired by ancient myths. Held at the Fitz Gibbon’s Pilot Hill estate each spring, the Events generally involved 100-200 people and featured copious nudity, dancing, and playful attire. The Pilot Hill Events also hosted well-known artists and art historians from around the country, such as Judy Chicago, Allan Kaprow, Marcia Tucker, and Bruce Nauman. Over the course of their lifetimes, John and Jane Fitz Gibbon developed a large private collection of post-1950s Californian art at their Pilot Hill home, consisting of approximately 400 works. Highlights of their collection were shown in the 1990 exhibition California Art, A to Z and Return, an alphabetic representation of Fitz Gibbon’s favorite California artists hosted at the Butler Institute of American Art in Youngstown, Ohio. An accompanying exhibition guide was published the same year. In 2002, highlights of their collection were again shown in The Pilot Hill of Contemporary Art, an exhibition hosted by the Crocker Art Museum in Sacramento. An accompanying exhibition catalog featured a lengthy retrospective written by John Fitz Gibbon on the California art scene of the previous 40 years. After suffering from Parkinson ’s disease for the last two decades of his life, John Fitz Gibbon, Sr., died on October 25th, 2009, in Santa Fe, New Mexico. He was survived by Jane, their daughter Kate and their son John, Jr. The following month, the city of Sacramento officially recognized Fitz Gibbon’s contributions in the fields of art criticism and arts advocacy.
Scope and Contents
The John and Jane Fitz Gibbon collection spans the 1950s to early 2000s, and features extensive documentation of prominent Northern Californian artists from the 1970s onward. John Fitz Gibbon’s papers include notes, annotated manuscript drafts, and extensive correspondence with artists of the day, particularly Joseph Raffael, William Wiley, and Don Hazlitt. His essays, reviews, and catalog guides are largely focused on artists whom he considered personal friends, and subjects include Joseph Raffael, Lance Richbourg, William Morehouse, Roy de Forest, Jack Stuppin, and Frank Owen, among many others. Between 1971 and 1981, the Fitz Gibbons staged twelve ‘Events’ at their Pilot Hill estate outside Placerville, CA. These Events, which were ostensibly outdoor theatrical celebrations inspired by ancient myths, featured hundreds of largely nude attendees performing, dancing, speaking, and playing music. These performances are well-documented in photographs, slides, and prints, as well as reels of 8mm, 16mm, and 35mm film, reel-to-reel tape, and various videocassette formats. There are also numerous reels of unlabeled and unidentified 8mm film and audiotape. Other material includes recordings of John Fitz Gibbon’s KPFA radio show, exhibition catalogs and publicity from favorite artists, candid snapshots of visitors to the Pilot Hill house, and teaching and lecture notes. Materials relating to Fitz Gibbon’s memorial on Dec. 20th, 2009, are included, as well.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Jane Fitz Gibbon; 2016 and 2017. Accessions MSS 2016-222, 2017-110, and 2017-129.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research. Note that material must be requested at least 36 hours in advance of intended use. Audiovisual materials are not available in original format, and must be reformatted to a digital use copy.
Art, American -- California.; Art criticism; Fitz Gibbon, Jane; Fitz Gibbon, John; KPFA (Radio station: Berkeley, Calif.)
- Series 1. Correspondence
  - #7 Letters from artists to John (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Tersh Boasberg, also called Emit (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence with Joseph and Lannis Raffael (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Letters written by John to art collector Bill Rees (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - #28 Writing and correspondence with Don Hazlitt (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - #28 Don Hazlitt sketches and correspondence with John (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Letters and an essay about Yale and Tersh Boasberg (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence with Bill Rees (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Sketches, articles, and writing for John's proposed 'California Building' at Yale (Box 8, Folder 8)
- Series 2. Events, 1971 - 1981
  - Subseries 1.1: Et in Arcadia Ego, 1971
    - 'Et in Arcadia Ego' event, 1971 - photographs (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - 'Et in Arcadia Ego' event, 1971 - slides (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - 'Et in Arcadia Ego' event, 1971 - oversize photo and note (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - 'Et in Arcadia Ego' event, 1971 - oversize photo (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - 'Et in Arcadia Ego' event, 1971 - oversize photo (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - 'Et in Arcadia Ego' event, 1971 - oversize photo (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - 'Et in Arcadia Ego' event, 1971 - oversize photo (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - #1 'Et in Arcadia Ego (Poussin) (sailboat)' - 'Arcadia Lunch Sailboat' - 12" reel of 35mm film (Box 17, Reel 4)
    - #9 John Fitz Gibbon - Et in Arcadia Ego event - one 5" reel of super 8mm film (Box 21, Reel 1)
    - #16 John Fitz Gibbon event film - Arcadia Lunch Sailboat - one 7" reel of 16mm film (Box 22, Reel 1)
    - #17 John Fitz Gibbon event film - Et in Arcadia Ego [Victor Faccinto?] - one 7" reel of 16mm film (Box 22, Reel 2)
  - Subseries 1.2: See More How Art Works, 1971
    - 'See More How Art Works' event, 1971 - slides (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - 'See More How Art Works' event, 1971 - photographs (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - #14 John Fitz Gibbon - See More How Art Works event - one reel of super 8mm film (Box 21, Reel 5)
  - Subseries 1.3: Good Spelling, 1972
    - 'Good Spelling' event, 1972 - slides (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - 'Good Spelling' event, 1972 - prints and photographs (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Subseries 1.4: Slaughtered Beef, 1973
    - 'Slaughtered Beef' event, 1973 - slides (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - 'Slaughtered Beef' event, 1973 - photographs (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - #8 John Fitz Gibbon videocassette - Slaughtered Beef (After Rembrandt) event - one 7" reel of color videotape (Box 21, Tape 3)
    - #2 John Fitz Gibbon event film - Slaughtered Beef (After Rembrandt) - one 12" reel of 35mm film (Box 23, Reel 5)
  - Subseries 1.5: Seven Deadly Sins, 1974
    - 'Seven Deadly Sins' event, 1974 - slides (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - 'Seven Deadly Sins' event, 1974 - photographs and prints (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - #4 Seven Deadly Sins master - 7" reel of videotape [damaged in beginning and broken in middle] (Box 17, Reel 9)
    - #5 Seven Deadly Sins 42 minute edit - 7" reel of videotape (Box 17, Reel 10)
      Scope and Contents
      "1974 Annual, Pilot Hill - Video - Paul Rhoads - Paul Blaise - Paul Lehman - 42 min. edit'
    - #11 John Fitz Gibbon - Seven Deadly Sins event - one reel of 8mm film (Box 21, Reel 4)
    - #3 John Fitz Gibbon event film - Seven Deadly Sins, 1974 - one 14" reel of 35mm film (Box 23, Reel 4)
  - Subseries 1.6: Paradise Couple, 1975
    - 'Paradise Couple' event, 1975 - prints (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - 'Paradise Couple' event, 1975 - slides (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - #6 John Fitz Gibbon videocassette - Paradise Couple event - one 5" reel of color videotape (Box 21, Tape 1)
  - Subseries 1.7: Unicorn Hunt, 1975
    - 'The Unicorn Hunt' event, 1975 - slides (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - 'The Unicorn Hunt' event, 1975 - photographs and prints (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - #24 Unicorn Hunt - 'Unicorn Hunt 1975 Pilot Hill, CA' - 9.5" reel of 16mm film (Box 16, Reel 3)
    - #8 John Fitz Gibbon Audiotape - sound for Unicorn Hunt event, 1975 - 5" reel of audiotape (Box 18, Reel 4)
    - #9 John Fitz Gibbon Audiotape - sound for Unicorn Hunt event, 1975, beginning with Unicorn Dance at corral - 5" reel of audiotape (Box 18, Reel 5)
    - #7 John Fitz Gibbon videocassette - Unicorn Hunt event - 7" reel of color videotape (Box 21, Tape 2)
  - Subseries 1.8: Peaceable Kingdom, 1976
    - 'Peaceable Kingdom' event, 1976 - slides and Hicks painting (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - 'Peaceable Kingdom' event, 1976 - photographs (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - John Fitz Gibbon videocassette - Lacin/Rhoads 1-3 - 20 minute Scotch videocassettes (Box 20, Tape 1 - 3)
      Handwritten annotation in accompanying document reads: "the Peaceable Kingdom 76 John Fitz Gibbon"
    - #20 John Fitz Gibbon event film - Peaceable Kingdom (after Edward Hicks) bicentennial, 1976 - one 7" reel of 16mm film (Box 22)
  - Subseries 1.9: Orpheus and Eurydice, 1977
    - 'Orpheus and Eurydice' event, 1977 - slides (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - John Fitz Gibbon videocassette - Orpheus 1-3 - 20 minute Scotch videocassettes (Box 19, Tape 1 - 3)
  - Subseries 1.10: Ninth Labor of Herakles, 1978
    - 'Ninth Labor of Herakles' event, 1978 - slides (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - 'Ninth Labor of Herakles' event, 1978 - prints and photographs (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - 'Ninth Labor of Herakles' event, 1978 - photographs (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - 'Ninth Labor of Herakles' event, 1978 - oversize photo (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - 'Ninth Labor of Herakles' event, 1978 - oversize photo (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - 'Ninth Labor of Herakles' event, 1978 - oversize photo (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - 'Ninth Labor of Herakles' event, 1978 - oversize photo (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - #19 Ninth Labor of Herakles - 'Hercules vs. the Amazons' - 9.5" reel of 16mm film (Box 16, Reel 2)
  - Subseries 1.11: The Triumph of Flora, 1980
    - Triumph of Flora' event, 1980 - photographs (1 of 2) (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - 'Triumph of Flora' event, 1980 - two prints of Judy Chicago (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - 'Triumph of Flora' event, 1980 - slides (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - 'Triumph of Flora' event, 1980 - photographs (2 of 2) (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - John Fitz Gibbon videocassette - Flora event and 7 Deadly Sins event - one 120 minute videocassette, 1980-04-27 (Box 20, Tape 4)
  - Subseries 1.12: Circe, 1981
    - 'Circe' event, 1981 - photographs (1 of 2) (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - 'Circe' event, 1981 - photographs (2 of 2) (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - 'Circe' event, 1981 - slides (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - #18 Circe - 10.5" reel of 16mm film (Box 16, Reel 1)
    - John Fitz Gibbon videocassette - John FitzGibbons event 1981: Assembled Rough Footage - one Maxell 1" (or 3/4") 60 minute videocassette (Box 20, Tape 6)
    - #13 John Fitz Gibbon - Circe event, 1-4 - four reels of 8mm film (Box 21, Reel 7 - 10)
  - Subseries 1.13: Misc. Event materials
    - CD-R - scans of event photographs, JFG draft writing (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Events negatives (1 of 6) (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Events negatives (2 of 6) (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Events negatives (3 of 6) (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Events negatives (4 of 6) (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Events negatives (5 of 6) (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Events negatives (6 of 6) (Box 13, Folder 10)
- Series 3. Exhibition Publicity
  - A (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - B (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - C (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Eduardo Carrillo (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Colescott Sales (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - D-E (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - F (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - G (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Robert Hudson (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - H (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - K (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - L (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - M (1 of 2) (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - M (2 of 2) (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - N (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - O (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - P (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - R (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - S (1 of 2) (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - S (2 of 2) (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - T (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - V (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - W (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - XYZ (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Group shows including John's artists of interest (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Pilot Hill exhibition postcards (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - 'Sexy' exhibition guides (Box 14, Folder 10)
- Series 4. Personal Files
  - City of Sacramento Recognition (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Letters of condolence to Jane Fitz Gibbon (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - John Fitz Gibbon memorial and eulogies (Box 9, Folder 4)
- Series 5. Published Writing
  - #1 Catalog essay on 35 artists (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - John's published writing (1 of 5) (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - John's published writing (2 of 5) (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - John's published writing (3 of 5) (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - John's published writing (4 of 5) (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - John's published writing (5 of 5) (Box 15, Folder 5)
- Series 6. Unpublished & Drafts of Writing
  - #25 Misc. notes & loose pages (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - #24 Notes, essays, and reviews (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - #23 Misc. essays and notes (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - #22 KPFA art criticism and description of tapes (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - #21 Writings on John's classes at Berkeley High and Cal State (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - #20 Essay on the Cal State U. development of 70s - 2000 art department (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - #19 Autobiography - the years between early 1968 through 1970 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - #18 Essays for catalogs or publication (2) (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - #17 Essays for catalogs or publication (3) (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - #16 Frank Owen (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - #15 William Wiley letters etc., to and from Wiley & John (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - #14 Essays for catalogs or publication (1) (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - #14 Essay on Nate Shiner (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - #14 Essay on Don Hazlitt (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - #13 Tony King, Jack Stuppen, William Wheeler, Bill Morehouse, Outdoor Painters - Plenair Painters Group (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - #12 3 Strikes Yer Out!!! - A-Z & Return (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - #11 Miscellaneous writing (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - #10 Other criticism in agreement with John's painting + sculpture in California 1976 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - #8 Essay on Ken Walton, who faked a Diebenkorn & sold it - article for Sacramento Bee (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - #6 Old friends (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - #5 Miscellaneous writings (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - #4 Teaching notes and essays (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - #3 "Hairy Who" - Chicago artists John recruited to teach at Cal State, Sacramento (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - #2 Art history essay on Synchronism, Cubism, Futurism, and handwritten notes (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - John's notebooks (1 of 6) (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - John's notebooks (2 of 6) (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - John's notebooks (3 of 6) (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - John's notebooks (4 of 6) (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - John's notebooks (5 of 6) (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - John's notebooks (6 of 6) (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Note accompanying box of John's writing (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - 7/2002 conversation with Joseph Raffael (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Joseph Raffael essay drafts and notes (1 of 2) (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Joseph Raffael essay drafts and notes (2 of 2) (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Notebooks: notes for Joseph Raffael essay (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Essay on Cal State Art dept. and artists in the 70s and 80s (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Misc. articles, publicity, and writing (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Essays on artists and inspirational teachers (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Writing on Allan Kaprow and the Events (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Crocker Catalog with annotations (copy of original) (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Annotated draft of Crocker art catalog (Box 9, Folder 2)
- Series 7. Artists Miscellaneous
  - Photocopy of 'Collaborations: William Allan, Robert Hudson, William Wiley' (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Snapshots of artist friends at Pilot Hill (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - #9 Photos of Eduardo Carrillo's burial in San Ignacio, La Paz (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - #10 John Fitz Gibbon - Alan Kaprow laundry event, late 1960s - two reels of super 8mm film (Box 21, Reel 2 - 3)
- Series 8. KPFA Recordings, 1967 - 1969
  - #1 and #3 John Fitz Gibbon KPFA show "Many Different Things" with Herbert Kohl, Victor Cruz, Ken Kinyan - two 11" reels of audiotape, 1969-01-11 (Box 17, Reel 5 - 6)
    “Many Different Things” - #1 -- Various including Herb Kohl and John FG, Victor Cruz (student poet), conga drumming; #3 – Various subjects live in the studio. “Taking the Twisted Way”, Herb Kohl and John FG with Ken Kinyan, hitchhiking minstrel.
  - #2 John Fitz Gibbon KPFA show "Art Review" - 11" reel of audiotape, 1967-08-10 (Box 17, Reel 7)
  - #4 John Fitz Gibbon KPFA show "Year End Review" - 11" reel of audiotape, 1968-12-26 (Box 17, Reel 8)
  - #5 John Fitz Gibbon KPFA - art criticism, Don Hazlitt - 7" reel of audiotape (Box 18, Reel 1)
  - #6 John Fitz Gibbon KPFA - art criticism, JFG with Howard Fried - 7" reel of audiotape (Box 18, Reel 2)
  - #7 John Fitz Gibbon KPFA - art criticism, Chicago Hairy Who artists Jim Nutt, Karl Wirsum, Gladys Nilsson, Leon Golub - 7" reel of audiotape, 1977-01-16 (Box 18, Reel 3)
  - #12 John Fitz Gibbon KPFA - Charles Amirkhanian, John Fitz Gibbon, Carol Law discuss Robert Arneson sculpture for New Moscone Convention Center - 7" reel of audiotape (Box 18, Reel 8)
  - #15 John Fitz Gibbon KPFA - art criticism, Carlos Villa and interview with 1960s Philippine-American artists - 7" reel of audiotape (Box 18, Reel 10)
  - #16 John Fitz Gibbon KPFA - Bill Allen, William Wegman, Kathy Goudell - 7" reel of audiotape (Box 18, Reel 11)
  - #18 John Fitz Gibbon KPFA - interview with Ellen Vanfleet for KPFA art review - 7" reel of audiotape (Box 18, Reel 13)
- Series 9. Other Media
  - #10 John Fitz Gibbon review of artwork by painter Joseph Raffael, Feb. 1978 - 7" reel of audiotape (Box 18, Reel 6)
  - #11 John Fitz Gibbon reviews California art in NY museums after a trip there - 7" reel of audiotape (Box 18, Reel 7)
    note from back: "Hi Padraigin This is a 14' 30" tape recorded June 16 at Sacto State's Audio Centre..."
  - #21 "Journey to the East" by Hermann Hesse, as interpreted through popular music by Kenneth H. Wendt - 5" reel of audiotape (Box 18, Reel 16)
  - Blaise 1-3 videocassettes (Box 19, Tape 4 - 6)
  - Final Performance: Art 490, Ant Death - one reel Scotch 1/2" videotape (Box 20, Tape 5)
- Series 10. Unidentified Media
  - Misc. slides (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Unlabeled negatives (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - John Fitz Gibbon L#5824 R1 - R3 - three reels of 16mm film (Box 17, Reel 1 - 3)
  - #13 John Fitz Gibbon Audiotape - unidentified tape - 7" reel of audiotape (Box 18, Reel 9)
  - #17 John Fitz Gibbon Audiotape - unidentified tape ("Practice Tape") - 3" reel of audiotape (Box 18, Reel 12)
  - #19 John Fitz Gibbon Audiotape - unidentified tape - 7" reel of audiotape (Box 18, Reel 14)
  - #20 John Fitz Gibbon Audiotape - unidentified tape - 7" reel of audiotape (Box 18, Reel 15)
  - Accompanying description to videocassettes (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Accompanying description to videocassettes (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - #15 John Fitz Gibbon - unidentified 8mm film (Box 21, Reel 6)
  - Unidentified 4" reel of Ektachrome film (Box 21, Reel 11)
  - Unidentified 4" reel of Ektachrome film (Box 21, Reel 12)
  - Unidentified 3" reel of 8mm film [07/69 style L. Robles?] (Box 21, Reel 13)
  - Unidentified 3" reel of 8mm film (Box 21, Reel 14)
  - Unidentified 3" reel of 8mm film (Box 21, Reel 15)
  - Unidentified 3" reel of 8mm film (Box 21, Reel 16)
  - Unidentified 3" reel of 8mm film (Box 21, Reel 17)
  - Unidentified 3" reel of super 8mm film (Box 21, Reel 18)
  - 3" reel of super 8mm film, labelled "Zoo" (Box 21, Reel 19)
  - Unidentified 3" reel of 8mm film (Box 21, Reel 20)
  - Unidentified 3" reel of 8mm film (Box 21, Reel 21)
  - #14 John's lecture slide collection - one box of negatives labelled "73 - 74" (Box 22, Carton 1)
  - Unidentified roll of duplicate 2" negatives (Box 22, Carton 2)
  - #12 5" reel of 8mm film labelled 'Laurie Briggs "Harmony" Film' (Box 23, Reel 1)
  - Unidentified 7" reel of 8mm film (Box 23, Reel 2)
  - Unidentified 7" reel of 8mm film (Box 23, Reel 3)
  - Unidentified 7" reel of 16mm film (Box 23, Reel 4)
  - Unidentified 7" reel of super 8mm film (Box 23, Reel 5)
  - Unidentified 7" reel of super 8mm film [Roll 2] (Box 23, Reel 6)
  - #23 Unidentified 5" reel of 16mm film (Box 23, Reel 1)
  - #22 Two unidentified 7" reels of 16mm film (Box 23, Reel 2 - 3)